# JAMES ALAFRIZ

# UX DESIGNER / INTEGRATED CREATIVE (HE/HIM)

#### CONTACT

≥ jalafriz@gmail.com

647.642.1973

m rovingcondor.com



# PROFILE

I am an integrated user experience deisnger and creative with applied experience in a variety of creative positions. My user-centred approach facilitates solutions to a wide variety of project objectives and I thrive in the problem solving process. A resolute preople-first team player who is energized by the success and growth of everyone in both my professional and personal life. Perpetual self-learning and improvement are part of my makeup.

# EDUCATION

#### UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

UX/UI Bootcamp Completed 2023-03

#### **GEORGE BROWN COLLEGE**

Graphic Design Diploma

Internet Technology Certificate

# RYERSON POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY

Business Management Program / Fconomics

# SKILLS

User-centred design / User experience design (user research, wireframing, user testing, prototyping, UI design, responsive web design, information architecture, interaction design, analytics)

Creative Problem Solving / Critical Thinking

Motivational Leadership & Mentorship (people-first philosophy, applied empathy, personal & professional growth)

### Art Direction

(video shoots, storyboarding, video editing, photo shoots, ad campaigns, marketing materials)

Applied Design Knowledge / Fundamentals (typography, illustration, photography, color theory, corporate identity)

Branding / Brand Guidelines (implementation / development)

Motion Graphics (storyboarding, editing)

Client-facing presentations

Project / Account Management / Budgeting

Adobe Creative Suite

(Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Premiere, After Effects)

#### Figma

HTML / CSS / Javascript

Microsoft Office Suite

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### CREATIVE DIRECTOR, CHIEF COMPLIANCE OFFICER (CCO)

Grizzle Media / Grizzle Investment Management | 2017 - Present

- Team lead for Creative Department and multidisciplinary
- Creative lead for usability, responsive web design, video, social accounts, infographics, editorial & print projects
- Hire and manage both in-house, freelance talent (Creative & IT)
- Build, manage & maintain relationships with vendors
- Account and budget management for all projects
- CCO for the GRZZ ETF (launched December 2021 on the NYSE)

#### ART DIRECTOR

LPi Communications | 2013 - 2017

- Creative lead & client presentations for advertising, marketing projects & responsive web design for Coca Cola, Kraft, Keurig, Old Dutch, Hockey Calgary (print & digital)
- Oversaw production team, collaborated with social and accounts teams
- Client presentations

### **COURSE INSTRUCTOR**

The Training Company | 2011 - 2013

- Created and led instructional courses for design & Adobe CS
- 100+ students passed/certified under my tutelage & mentorship

#### **SENIOR DESIGNER**

BStreet Communications | 2008 - 2010

- Collaborate with Creative, Production & Account teams to develop projects from concept through production (print & digital)
- Client-presentations for pitches and creative concepts
- Clients included Coca Cola, Weston Foods, Corby, Kinder & Ferrero

#### **CREATIVE DIRECTOR**

**Sagemedica** | 2001 - 2007

- Creative Department Team Lead
- Clients included Pfizer, Roche, Amgen
- Led and collaborated with creative team to design and develop projects from concept through production (print & digital)
- Client presentations for pitches and creative concepts
- Oversaw production and on-time approval/delivery of final layouts/proofs
- Liaise with Account Managers, in-house staff, freelancers and suppliers